 How to practice a language !

 Here are some exercises to help you improving your skills in any programming language.
 The purpose of this exercise sheet is to allow anybody learning a new language to practise. Exercises are ordered by difficulty.
 The exercises are taken from practical session of EPITA's first year.
 Document will be updated with new exercises and corrections are available for some languages.
 Since I am far from knowing every programming language, some exercise may not be as easy as they could be.
 Feel free to send me corrections for languages that are not available yet,
 new exercises ideas or any mistakes that I could have made !
 Nothing will be clearly explained, you will just have exercises and corrections.
 You need to look for answers on the internet (stackoverflow.com is good for example) and search by yourself.
 Tutorials are available all around the internet, but searching by yourself helps you learning about things
 you were not looking for !
 Good luck :)

 Create a new project for the language you want to learn and add this file with the 
 right extension (.c for c, .cpp for C++, .cs for C#, etc.) regarding the language.
 You will need to add the corresponding headers/library/etc.



Part One:


FIXME: Declare variables
Declare two variables: an integer named "age", and a string named "name" with corresponding values (your name and age)

FIXME: Print
Print the following sentence in the console "You are NAME and you are AGE years old !". Don't forget to add a newline at the end

FiXME: Concatenation
Create a new string variable called "hello" which value is "Hello ". Add "name" at the end of "hello" (Concatenation) then print it

FIXME: Array
create a new string array called "shoppingList", with three elements of your choice. Create an int variable containing the number of
elements in "shoppingList" (using a function of the array/using the array)

FIXME: For-loop - Integer
Create a simple for-loop for an integer "i" going from 1 to 10 that print the value of "i"

FIXME: For-loop - shoppingList
Create a for loop that iterate through "shoppingList" and prints each element.

FIXME: Foreach-loop
Do the same with a foreach-loop.

FIXME: If-statement
Modify the first for-loop (with i from 1 to 10) such that it prints "(value of i) is even" when "i" is divisible
by 2 (You may want to learn more about "modulo" (%)). Else, print "(value of i) is odd".

FIXME: Sum Up
Create a string variable called "element" with the value of your choice. Then create a for-loop that checks if "shoppingList" contains 
"element". If yes, print "You have to buy (value of element) !", and stop the loop (search how to stop a loop).
If not, print "Nope, you don't need (value of "element")".





Part Two:


FIXME: Functions - Ascii
Create a function that returns nothing and which doesn't takes any parameter. It should just be named "TriForce"
and print the TriForce symbol (one triangle over two other ones, can be found on internet) with "TRIFORCE"
Don't forget to call the function !


FIXME: Functions - One parameter
Create a function that takes a string as parameter and returns "Hello (value of string) !"

FIXME: Functions - Multiple parameters
Create a function that takes two integers as parameters and returns the addition of these two.
You can do the same with multiplication, subtraction and division.

FIXME: User entry
Create a string variable that takes what the user enter in the console as value. Then print "You entered (value of string)"

FIXME: While loop
Create a while loop that takes a number and divides it by 2 until it is less than 3

FIXME: do-While loop
Do the same with a do-while loop

FIXME: Random generator
Create a function that returns a random number

FIXME: Random generator with bounds
Create another function that returns a random number between two bounds given as parameters.

FIXME: Multidimensional array
Create a two dimensional int array of 3 columns and 3 rows. Use 2 for-loops to add a random number
between 1 and 9 in each of the 9 rooms.
You may use one of the two previously created function.
Then print them such that they appear like this (with [x1,x9] being the 9 random integers):
{x1,x2,x3,}
{x4,x5,x6,}
{x7,x8,x9,}


FIXME: Switch
Create a Switch that takes an integer "a" and return a sentence regarding the value of a
(Create 3 statements for 3 specific values and a default one)

FIXME: logic Gates
Create 7 functions for each logic gates (And, Or, No, Nand, Nor, Xnor, Xor).
Each function takes two booleans as parameters and returns the result of the logic gate.
(or You can do it with a switch and only one function)

FIXME - Reverse
Create a function that reverse a string
